Finding Aid for League of Women Voters of Detroit records, 1930-1988
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
League of Women Voters of Detroit records 1930-1988
League of Women Voters of Detroit.
89482 Bm 2
Board meeting minutes, correspondence, newsletters, position statements on various statements, and pamphlets and other publications; also visual materials; subjects covered by files include environmental quality, education, and women's rights issues.
4 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This record group was acquired from League of Women Voters of Detroit in 1989 (Donor no. 7678 ).
The record group is open to research.
The League of Women Voters is a nonpartisan organization which promotes informed citizen participation in government. The League does not endorse candidates or parties, but it does study issues and act on those issues. The League of Women Voters of Detroit has shown special concern toward environmental and educational issues.
The records of the Detroit League of Women Voters cover the years 1930 to 1988, although its primary coverage is 1960 through 1980. The record group measures four linear feet in size and is arranged alphabetically by subject. Included are minutes from board meetings, correspondence, newsletters, League positions on various bills, pamphlets and other publications. Minutes from annual meetings are included in the board meetings file. One file contains correspondence from the Wayne County League of Women Voters dating back to 1930.
The largest files in the record group concerns environmental quality, education (busing, desegregation, and teacher certification), housing, human resources and women's issues (abortion, ERA and mortgage credit). The extensive environmental files cover air pollution, land use, phosphates and clean water.
Subjects:
Detroit (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Education--Michigan--Detroit.; Environmental protection--Michigan--Detroit.; League of Women Voters of Detroit.; Michigan--Politics and government.; Women--Michigan--Detroit--Societies and clubs.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
County government.; Government buildings--Michigan--Wayne County.; Government employees.; Wayne County (Mich.); Wayne County (Mich.)--Government buildings.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Administrative Office Files
  (arranged alphabetically)
  - Board Meetings
    - 1966 (Box 1)
    - 1967 (Box 1)
    - 1968 (Box 1)
    - 1969 (Box 1)
    - 1970 (Box 1)
  - Campaign Financing 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - China 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Citizens to Advance Public Education (CAPE) 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Communism 1947-1951 (Box 1)
  - Congress 1971-1979
    - Letters from Congressmen (Box 1)
    - Reorganization (Box 1)
  - Courts
    - City (Box 1)
    - County (Box 1)
    - State
      - 1949-1956, 1961, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 1)
      - 1970-1982 (Box 1)
  - Detroit
    - Charter Revision 1971-1973 (Box 2)
    - Police 1966-1973 (Box 2)
    - Taxation 1962, 1966-1968 (Box 2)
    - Urban Crisis 1951, 1960, 1976-1979 (Box 2)
  - Education
    - Decentralization 1965-1983 (Box 2)
    - Desegregation
      - Busing 1969-1972, 1973-1981 (Box 2)
      - Coalition for Peaceful Integration 1969-1972, 1973-1981 (Box 2)
    - Finances
      - Distribution of Education Money (DOM) 1972-1981 (Box 2)
    - Millage 1966-1971, 1972-1978
      - Tax and Education Reform (Box 2)
      - Tuition Tax Credit (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1965-1974, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Task Force
      - 1969-February 1973 (Box 2)
      - March 1973-June 1973 (Box 2)
      - July 1973-1975; 1979 (Box 2)
    - Teacher Certification
      - Accountability 1972-1974, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Energy 1975-1980 (Box 2)
  - Environmental Issues
    - Acid Rain; Clean Air 1970-1988 (Box 2)
    - Bottle Bill HB4296 1974-1977 (Box 2)
    - Environmental Protection Agency 1970-1975, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Environmental Issues (cont.)
    - Environmental Quality Newsletters August 1971-November 1975 (Box 2)
    - Lake Erie Basin (Box 3)
      - Oil and Gas Drilling 1963-1982 (Box 3)
    - Lake Erie Letter 1969-1975, 1981, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Land Use 1971-1980 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous 1968-1988
      - Position Papers (Box 3)
      - Press Releases (Box 3)
    - Natural Resources Letter 1982 (Box 3)
    - Nuclear Power
      - Radioactive Waste 1969-1988 (Box 3)
    - Pesticides 1969 (Box 3)
    - Phosphates H.B. 4015 1970-1972, 1977 (Box 3)
    - River Rouge Basin: Pernick Drain 1969-1977 (Box 3)
    - Shorelands: Erosion 1969-1974 (Box 3)
    - Solid Waste Management
      - Hazardous Waste Disposal 1971-1983 (Box 3)
    - Water 1956-1983
      - Clean Water (Box 3)
      - Water Policy (Box 3)
  - Executive Branch 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Government Financing 1972-1984 (Box 3)
  - Health Care 1981-1985 (Box 3)
  - Home Rule for Washington D.C. 1962-1967, 1973-1978 (Box 3)
  - Housing
    - 1947-1956, 1963-1969 (Box 3)
    - 1970-1980, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Equal Housing Opportunity 1967-1973 (Box 3)
    - Homesteading; Urban Renewal 1968-1979 (Box 3)
    - Housing and Urban Development (HUD) 1972-1979 (Box 3)
    - Zoning 1950-1968 (Box 3)
  - Insurance 1979, 1981
    - Anti-Redlining (Box 3)
    - No-Fault (Box 3)
  - Intergovernmental Relations Within Michigan 1980-1982 (Box 3)
  - International Relations 1969-1979 (Box 3)
  - Metropolitan Integration Study 1971-1972, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Constitutional Convention 1948, 1957-1962, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Election Laws 1975-1979 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Taxation 1959, 1967, 1971-1977, 1983
    - Fiscal Problems (Box 4)
    - Revenue Sharing (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous 1943-1987, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - National Security 1982-1984 (Box 4)
  - Photographic Slides
    - Wayne County 1978 (Box 4)
  - Social Services
    - Juvenile Justice System 1964-1979 (Box 4)
    - Welfare
      - 1963-1969 (Box 4)
      - 1971-1982 (Box 4)
  - State Issues
    - Public Welfare 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Transportation
    - SEMTA 1972-1982 (Box 4)
  - Wayne County Council 1952 (Box 4)
  - Wayne County League of Women Voters 1930-1931 (Box 4)
  - Wayne County Government
    - Home Rule
      - 1944-1963 (Box 4)
      - 1964-1972 (Box 4)
      - 1973-1982 (Box 4)
  - Women's Issues
    - Abortion; Equal Rights Amendment 1971-1985 (Box 4)
    - Mortgage Credit 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Women's Assembly III 1982 (Box 4)